# Changyeon Kim

🛘 (+82) 10-9020-3925 | 🗷 changyeon.kim@kaist.ac.kr | 🏕 changyeon.page | 🖸 csmile-1006 | 🞓 Changyeon Kim

# Research Interest\_

My research interest lies on applying RL algorithms to challenging tasks where reward specification is burdensome. To this end, I am focusing on designing RL algorithms to tackle practical and challenging scenarios like unseen novel environments and environments without well-shaped rewards. Especially, I am interested in human preference based reinforcement learning. I am also broadly interested in areas related to RL, including RL leveraging pre-trained representation learning, language-conditioned RL, and offline RL.

# **Education**

### Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology

PhD in Artificial Intelligence

Advisor: Jinwoo Shin and Kimin Lee

**Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology** 

B.Sc. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND MATHEMATICS (MINOR)

Daejeon, S.Korea

Mar. 2022 - Present

Daejeon, S.Korea

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2021

# **Publications**

C: Conference, W: Workshop, P: Preprint, \*: Equal contribution

#### [C2] Guide Your Agent with Adaptive Multimodal Rewards

CHANGYEON KIM, YOUNGGYO SEO, HAO LIU, LISA LEE, JINWOO SHIN, HONGLAK LEE, KIMIN LEE

· Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2023.

• Previously accepted to ICML Workshop on New Frontiers in Learning, Control, and Dynamical Systems (ICMLW), 2023.

#### [C2] Preference Transformer: Modeling Human Preferences using Transformers for RL

CHANGYEON KIM\*, JONGJIN PARK\*, JINWOO SHIN, HONGLAK LEE, PIETER ABBEEL, KIMIN LEE

• International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2023.

Kigali, Rwanda

New Orleans, USA

May, 2023.

Dec, 2023.

#### [W1] Dynamics-Augmented Decision Transformer for Offline Dynamics Generalization

CHANGYEON KIM\*, JUNSU KIM\*, YOUNGGYO SEO, KIMIN LEE, HONGLAK LEE, JINWOO SHIN

Neural Information Processing Systems Workshop on Offline Reinforcement Learning (NeurIPSW), 2022.

New Orleans, LA, USA

Nov, 2022.

#### [C1] Collecting the Public Perception of AI and Robot Rights

Gabriel Lima, Changyeon Kim, Seungho Ryu, Chihyoung Jeon, Meeyoung Cha

Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW), 2020.

Online Oct. 2020.

# [P1] MOI-Mixer: Improving MLP-Mixer with Multi Order Interactions in Sequential Recommendation

Hojoon Lee, Dongyoon Hwang, Sunghwan Hong, Changyeon Kim, Seungryong Kim, Jaegul Choo

· ArXiv Preprint.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

LISA LEE (GOOGLE RESEARCH)

# External Collaborator

• Developed an imitation learning algorithm [C2] using multimodal representations for improving generalization ability in unseen variations.

**External Collaborator** Remote

HONGLAK LEE (UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN)

Mar. 2022 - present

Apr. 2023 - Aug. 2023

- Developed an imitation learning algorithm [C2] using multimodal representations for improving generalization ability in unseen variations.
- Developed a reinforcement learning algorithm [W1] for improving generalization ability in varying dynamics.
- Developed a preference-based reinforcement learning algorithm [C2] for modeling non-Markovian human preferences.

**SEPTEMBER 22, 2023** CHANGYEON KIM · RÉSUMÉ

#### **Machine Learning Engineer**

KAKAO, RECOMMENDATION TEAM

Seongnam, S.Korea

Dec. 2020 - Feb. 2022

- Developed ML platform for recommendation system.
- Developed Python backend for a web application providing data analysis and visualization of Kakao data.
- Implemented data pipeline from user feedback to refined user-item interaction matrix data.
- Deployed DropoutNet for providing qualitative recommendations to cold-start users.

Research Intern Seongnam, S.Korea

KAKAO, RECOMMENDATION TEAM

Jun. 2020 - Aug. 2020

- · Developed an advanced similar recommendation model for Piccoma (cartoon platform of Kakao Japan).
- · Conducted research on relationships between offline/online evaluation on the recommendation system.

Research Intern Daejeon, S.Korea

DATA SCIENCE GROUP, INSTITUTE OF BASIC SCIENCE

Jul. 2019 - Nov. 2020

- · Conducted research on how much human rights can be granted to robots using AMT (Amazon Mechanical Turk) [C1].
- Implemented BiLSTM model for extracting game higlight by game log.
- · Conducted research identifying the "Pilgrimage" articles and analyzing its pattern in Naver News corpora.

Research Interen Seoul, S.Korea

NETMARBLE

Jun. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Implemented algorithm for detecting "fraud" account in online-game
- Analyzed repetitive group reaction from time-series data of game activities.

# **Honors & Awards**

2023	<b>Travel Award</b> , International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)	Kigali, Rwanda
2019	Dean's List (Fall Semester), Department of Engineering, KAIST	Daejeon, S.Korea
2019	Line Scholarship (Fall Semester), School of Computing, KAIST	Daejeon, S.Korea
2017 - 19	National Science and Engineering Scholarship, Korea Ministry of Science and ICT	Daejeon, S.Korea
2017	Kwanjeong Scholarship (Spring Semester), KAIST	Daejeon, S.Korea

# **Academic Services**

Workshop Reviewer ICML Workshop on New Frontiers in Learning, Control, and Dynamical Systems (Frontiers4LCD) 2023

# **Skills**

ML/DL Pytorch, Pytorch-lightning, JAX/Flax

**Programming** Python, C++

Big Data Kafka, SQL, MongoDB, Hadoop, Trino(Presto)

**DevOps** Git, Docker, Kubernetes

**Languages** Korean (Native), English (Fluent), Japanese (Advanced)